jcpenney.net 2016-06-17

# privacy policy - JCPenney

####  J. C. Penney Corporation, Inc. Privacy Policy (rev. 7/24/15)  
  
---  
  
The following Privacy Policy applies to information collected by J. C. Penney Corporation, Inc., its subsidiaries and affiliates (“JCPenney”) in the United States and Puerto Rico at JCPenney’s retail stores and through our websites and mobile applications. .  
  
  * the information we collect 
  * using the information we collect 
  * information we share with others 
  * cookies and other technologies 

  * safeguarding the Information we collect 
  * your choices regarding the use of information we collect 
  * notice to California residents – your California privacy rights  
  * updating your JCPenney contact information 

  * unauthorized charges 
  * children’s privacy 
  *   * international customer privacy 

  * changes to this policy 

**the information  we collect**  
  
---  
  
We collect information from various sources, including from you, your transactions, your visits to our stores or websites, or your use of our mobile applications or in-store guest Wi-Fi service. We may also obtain information about you from third party sources.

**information you provide -** When you interact with JCPenney, we collect information, including personal information, from you. Personal information is information that identifies you, such as your name, physical and email addresses, telephone numbers, and your credit/debit card number, or driver’s license number. Examples of such interactions are:

  * You make a purchase, return or exchange;
  * You create and use an account on one of our websites (e.g. a jcpenney.com account or a jcpenney rewards.com account/profile);
  * You sign up to receive coupons, sales alerts and promotional emails or text messages;
  * You join a loyalty program (e.g. JCPenney Rewards) or club;
  * You participate in a contest, sweepstakes, promotion, survey or consumer research:
  * You create or update a gift registry, or a save for later list;
  * You submit a rating or review, or other user-generated content that may be posted to our website;
  * You request customer service or contact us;
  * You apply for a JCPenney Credit Card account;
  * You use JCPenney’s pages on social media sites (e.g. Facebook and Twitter);
  * You enable location-based functionalities through your mobile device, or when using the JCPenney mobile application; or
  * You ask us to ship an order to a gift recipient.

**information from other sources -** We may receive information about you from other sources and third parties. For example, if you have a JCPenney Credit Card, we receive application and account information from the credit card issuing bank. We also obtain data from third party parties to improve the accuracy of and add to what we know about our customers. This may improve the relevance of the offers or product recommendations we provide you or enhance our ability to contact you. For example, we may work with other websites and services to present advertising to groups of our customers when they visit those sites. Non-personal data received by us from this process is used to analyze the effectiveness of such advertising.

We may also collect data that is publicly available. For example, information you submit in a public forum (e.g. a blog, chat room or social network) can be read, collected or used by us or others, and could be used to personalize your experience. You are responsible for the information you submit in those instances.

**automated information collection -** We and our service providers may automatically collect information when you visit our websites, use our mobile applications, or use our in-store guest Wi-Fi service.

**our websites -** We and our service providers automatically collect such data as internet protocol (IP) address, device operating system and browser type, the address of the website you are coming from, if any, and the path you take through our website (e.g. the pages you look at and the items you click on).

**our mobile application -** We and our service providers automatically collect information such as  the type of mobile device, operating system, browser being used, the connection speed, any unique identifiers associated with advertising and analytics assigned by our service provider, the device manufacturer, or your internet service provider for your device,  the IP address of your device, time stamps, bar code or other information if you use the scanning feature, and information about the way you use our mobile applications. 

**in-store guest Wi-Fi service -** We may make guest Wi-Fi service available to visitors to JCPenney stores. Some examples of information collected automatically in connection with that services, are:

  * Usage data (e.g. number of users by store, types of websites visited while using the service)
  * Session data (e.g. how long a user stays on the guest Wi-Fi service)
  * Device and browser data (e.g. type of device, device ID, type of browser, IP address)

Also, when you use the guest Wi-Fi service in our stores, we collect precise, real-time information about the location of your device.  If you do not wish this to occur, please refrain from using our in-store guest Wi-Fi service.

**cookies -** We or our service providers use “cookies” to recognize you as you use or return to our websites.  We or our service providers also may use pixel tags (also called "web beacons”), which allow us or them to know if a certain page was visited, an email was opened, or if ads on our website or other sites were effective. For more information, see the “cookies and other technologies” section below.

**precise location information -** Our mobile applications collect precise, real-time information about the location of your device. You must first provide permission through your device before our mobile applications obtain such information from technologies such as GPS, Wi-Fi, or cell tower triangulation (or a combination of these technologies). We and our service providers may use this information to: provide location-based services such as “store locator” or “find item in store"; to improve your in-store experience in conjunction with our use of wireless beacons; or to provide location-based notifications about our products and services. You may opt-out from further allowing one of our mobile applications to have access to your location data by adjusting the permissions in your mobile device or uninstalling the application. 

**in-store cameras -** We use in-store cameras for security purposes and operational purposes such as measuring traffic patterns.  
  
**using the information we collect**  
  
We use the information we collect to offer, improve, and provide our products and services and to carry out various business functions. We may combine or use the services of third party companies to combine information about you that we collect online, in our stores, through mobile applications and from third party sources.  Examples of how that information is used include:

**product and service fulfillment**

  * To complete, fulfill, manage and communicate with you about purchases, orders, payments, returns/exchanges, or requests for information about our products and services;
  * To establish and service your account on one of our websites (e.g. a jcpenney.com account or a jcpenneyrewards.com account/profile);
  * To provide customer service and alert you to product information, including product recalls;
  * To provide services such as gift registry or saved items lists; and
  * To administer loyalty programs (e.g. JCPenney Rewards).

**our marketing purposes**

  * To send information about our products, services, and promotions, such as direct mail, coupons, mobile text alerts, and emails;
  * To provide interactive features of our websites and mobile applications, such as product ratings and reviews, share with a friend, find item in store, store ads, push notifications, and store locator;
  * To identify product and service preferences, so our customers and visitors can be informed of new or additional products, services and promotions of possible interest; and
  * To administer contests, sweepstakes, promotions, surveys, and focus groups.

**internal operations**

  * To improve the effectiveness of our websites, stores, mobile applications, merchandise selections, customer service and marketing efforts;
  * To conduct research and analysis; and
  * To perform other business activities as needed.

**fraud prevention and legal compliance**

  * To detect and prevent fraudulent transactions and monitor against theft;
  * To protect the security and integrity of our websites and our business; and
  * To assist law enforcement and respond to legal/regulatory inquiries.

**information we share with others**

**JCPenney family -** We share information we collect with affiliated companies and licensees (e.g. the optical and photography departments in our stores) within the JCPenney family of businesses.

**service providers -** We disclose or otherwise make available information we collect with other companies that help with our business operations.  Examples include providers of services related to e-mail communications, mobile marketing, analytics, product fulfillment, web hosting, and fraud detection; payment processors; or entities that help us market our products and services. For example, we share information with our international fulfillment service provider, Borderfree, for the purpose of facilitating the sale and fulfillment of online purchases that our customers choose to ship internationally.  We also provide information to Synchrony Bank and other service providers in connection with the JCPenney credit programs.

**third-party marketing -** We may provide information about you to third party companies or organizations.  These entities may use that information to market their products and services to you. To opt-out of such sharing go to the “your choices regarding the use of information we collect” section of this policy.

**registry partners -** If you create a gift registry, we will share your event information with our gift registry partners, such as The Knot and The Bump, and your event information will be accessible on our websites, through our mobile applications and in our stores.

**legal or safety requirements -** We may disclose information we collect when we believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with the law; to enforce or apply applicable terms and conditions and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property or safety of our business, our customers or others.

**business transfers -** If the ownership of JCPenney or all or part of a business within the JCPenney Family were to change, information about customers pertinent to JCPenney or that business’s operations would likely be transferred to, or licensed for use by, the new owner.  The applicable member of the JCPenney Family might also retain a copy of that information.

**sharing aggregate Information -** We may share aggregate information (information that does not directly identify any individual) with third parties for lawful purposes.  
  
---  
  
**our use of cookies and  other technologies**

**"web browser" cookies -** A cookie is a small data file stored by your web browser on your computer or device. When you visit our websites, cookies allow us or our service providers to recognize you by an identification number in the cookie. **** We and our service providers use "cookies" to collect and analyze information about your browsing and buying activity on our site (whether through the Internet or mobile applications). For instance, the data stored in cookies allows us and our service providers to understand how you clicked to our site and what pages you click on during your visit to our site, as well as how you use our mobile applications. Knowing how you prefer to shop allows us to improve your shopping experience.

If you use the privacy settings on your web browser to disable cookies, you can still browse our websites, but you may not have as exceptional a shopping experience as one that is specifically tailored to your needs. If you disable or block cookies, you will not be able to make purchases on our websites. 

**pixel tag -  **A "pixel tag" (also called a web beacon or a clear gif) is a tiny graphic image placed on website pages and in emails, advertising and other marketing communications that allows us and our service providers to determine whether you have performed specific actions. When you access those pages or open email messages, or click on advertising, the pixel tags generate a notice of that action to us, or our service providers.  That information is used to analyze what our visitors like to do on our site or mobile applications, and the effectiveness of our features and advertising, as well as interactions with our e-mail and advertising.

**wireless beacons**   \- A wireless beacon is a small device that we may use as part of our in-store experience. Wireless beacons broadcast a signal that can be received by compatible devices, such as a mobile phone or tablet, when those devices are within the proximity of the beacon. We and our service providers may use wireless beacons in conjunction with the JCPenney mobile application to personalize and enhance your in-store shopping experience and to understand your interests so that we can provide relevant notifications, offers, and promotions.

**flash cookies  - **A flash cookie (also known as a Local Shared Object) is a data file stored on your computer by the websites you visit using Adobe Flash technology. Flash cookies are persistent, meaning that they do not go away when you exit your browser. While it may be possible to manage Flash cookies through your browser, depending on your browser version, you may choose to manage the use of Flash cookies via the Settings Manager on Adobe’s website at:  <http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html>.  We and our service providers may use flash cookies to enable or control flash-based content, to detect or prevent fraud, and for other uses similar to those of webbrowser cookies discussed earlier in this section.

**analytics services** - JCPenney uses third party analytics companies, such as IBM Digital Analytics and Google Analytics to provide analysis of our customers’ website, mobile application, and in-store experiences. These companies collect and analyze information about how people interact with us through our web-based, mobile, and in-store media, including information about browsing and buying activities. To perform some of these services, they may collect and use information from first- and third-party cookies, from wi-fi, mobile applications, or in-store wireless beacons. In addition, analytics companies, such as Google Analytics and Adobe Analytics also provide services that analyze information collected from cookies and pixel tags (web beacons) regarding visits to certain portions of jcpenney.com that are operated for JCPenney by third parties, such as our Sports Fan Shop, Bali and Levolor blinds and shades pages, and personalized jewelry pages. 

  * To learn more about IBM Digital Analytics’ privacy practices, [click here](http://www.ibm.com/software/marketing-solutions/privacy/index.html). You may opt-out of data collection by IBM Digital Analytics on jcpenney.com by clicking on the opt-out choice set forth below.  Please note that this opt-out only applies to data collected on jcpenney.com and not to data that might be collected by IBM Digital Analytics on any other sites.

_total opt-out_. Your data is not collected by IBM Digital Analytics data collection front-end servers, and consequently is not included in IBM Digital Analytics reporting. To opt-out, [click here](http://www88.jcpenney.com/privacy/privacy_handler.php?dest=http://www88.jcpenney.com/privacy/optout.html&act=opt_out).

_cancel opt-out_ setting will again allow IBM Digital Analytics to capture all web actions, and includes the data collected in IBM Digital Analytics reporting. To cancel opt-out, [click here](http://www88.jcpenney.com/privacy/privacy_handler.php?dest=http://www88.jcpenney.com/privacy/cancel.html&act=optin).

[Click here to view your current IBM Digital Analytics opt-out status](http://www88.jcpenney.com/privacy/getStatus.php?bg=FFFFFFF&im=)

  * To learn more about Google Analytics’ privacy practices and any opt-out choices it offers, [click here](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html).  
  * To learn more about Adobe Analytics’ privacy practices or to opt- out of cookies set to facilitate reporting by Adobe Analytics, [click here](http://www.omniture.com/en/privacy/policy).

Please note that your opt-out status may be maintained by placement of an “opt-out” cookie on your device.  If the cookie is removed or deleted, or you upgrade to a new version of your browser, change browsers or visit us from a different device, you will need to repeat this process to indicate your preference.

**technology used to serve  advertising**: We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads (e.g. banners or links) tailored to your individual interests based on how you browse and shop on jcpenney.com and other sites over time, and to perform tracking and reporting functions with respect to our ads. We also allow third-party companies to collect certain information when you visit our site and to use that information to serve ads for JCPenney products or services, or the products or services of other companies when you visit our site or other sites. For instance, we and third-party vendors, such as Google, use first- and third-party cookies, pixel tags and other technologies to inform, optimize and serve ads based upon a user’s past visits to our website and to report upon how our ad impressions and other ad services are related to jcpenney.com.  We may combine and associate the information we collect through these technologies with other information we have collected from and about you. This collective information may be used, among other things, for interest-based advertising (also called “online behavioral advertising”) in order to personalize your online experience, improve our website, evaluate the effectiveness of our advertising, and to tailor our marketing to you.

At this time, we do not respond to browser “do not track” signals, but we do provide you the option to opt-out of interest-based advertising, as well as the other choices described in the “your choices” section of this policy.

To learn more about interest-based advertising and how to “opt-out” of interest based advertising programs from participating companies, please go to the Network Advertising Initiative website at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> or the Digital Advertising Alliance website at <http://www.aboutads.info/>. Please note that the opt-outs you make on one or both of those websites only apply to the receipt of interest-based advertising from participating companies.  You may still receive other types of online advertising from participating companies, and the websites you visit may still collect information for other purposes. Also, your opt-out status may be maintained by placement of an “opt-out” cookie on your computer.  If the cookie is removed or deleted, or you upgrade to a new version of your browser, change browsers or visit us from a different computer or device, you will need to repeat this process to indicate your opt-out preference.  
  
**safeguarding the information we collect**  
---  
  
We have physical, technical and procedural safeguards in place to protect the personal information we collect. Also we use Secure Socket Layering (SSL) technology to encrypt your credit or debit card information, including the account number, while it is transmitted over the Internet from your computer.  SSL is an industry standard technology for secure online transactions. We also require service providers to have safeguards in place to protect the personal information that they collect, use, share, and store on our behalf.  
  
**your choices regarding the use of the information we collect**  
  
**postal mail**  

If you do not want to receive coupons and other promotional mail from JCPenney, you may:

  * write to us at J.C. Penney Corporation, Inc., P.O. Box 10001, Dallas, TX. 75301-7311, Attention: Corporate Customer Relations
  * call us at 1.800.322.1189
  * email us at [privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com](mailto:privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com?)

**emails**  

If you are currently receiving promotional email offers and updates from JCPenney, you may unsubscribe at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe hyperlink contained in our promotional emails. If you have registered on jcpenney.com, you can cancel your email subscription through your account. You may also:

  * call us at 1.800.322.1189 or
  * email us at [privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com](mailto:privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com?)
  * write to us at J. C. Penney Corporation, Inc., P.O. Box 10001, Dallas, TX 75301-7311, Attention: Corporate Customer Relations

Please note that even if you unsubscribe from promotional email offers and updates, we may still contact you by email for transactional purposes.  Some examples are communications regarding your order status, JCPenney Rewards if you are a member, customer service inquiries, service or reminder notices, and recalls.

**mobile marketing messages**

If you are currently receiving marketing text messages from JCPenney, you may tell us to stop sending them by using the opt-out functionality contained in the next marketing text message you receive. After we receive your opt-out, we will send you a final text message to confirm the opt-out.

**sharing with other companies for their marketing purposes**

If you prefer that we:

  * NOT share information about you with companies outside the JCPenney family for their marketing purposes, or
  * NOT share your JCPenney credit account history information with affiliated companies within the JCPenney family

Please let us know by:

  * writing to us at J. C. Penney Corporation, Inc., P.O. Box 10001, Dallas, TX 75301-7311, Attention: Corporate Customer Relations, 
  * calling us at 1.800.322.1189
  * email us at [privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com](mailto:privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com?)

If you prefer that we:

  * NOT share information about you with any of the companies outside the JCPenney family that we have authorized to contact you regarding their products or services, or 
  * NOT share your JCPenney credit account history information with affiliated companies within the JCPenney family

Please let us know by: 

  * writing to us at J. C. Penney Corporation, Inc., P.O. Box 10001, Dallas, TX 75301-7311, Attention: Corporate Customer Relations, 
  * calling us at 1.800.322.1189
  * email us at [_privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com_](mailto:privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com?)

******notice to California residents - your California privacy rights**

Under California law, a California resident with whom JCPenney has an established relationship has the right to request certain information with respect to the types of personal information JCPenney has shared with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, and the identities of those third parties, within the immediately preceding calendar year, subject to certain exceptions. All requests for such information must be in writing and sent to:  J. C. Penney Corporation, Inc., P.O. Box 10001, Dallas, TX 75301.  Attention: Corporate Customer Relations.

This same California law permits JCPenney to provide you, in response to your written request, with a cost-free means to choose not to have your information shared rather than providing the above described information. You may exercise that choice by any of the means described under “sharing with other companies with their marketing purposes".

**updating your JCPenney contact information**

If you have created a jcpenney.com account, a gift registry or a jcpenneyrewards.com account/profile, you can update your information by signing back into your account or registry.  You can also update or correct your name, address, telephone number, or email address by: 

  * writing to us at J. C. Penney Corporation, Inc., P.O. Box 10001, Dallas, TX 75301-7311, Attention: Corporate Customer Relations

  * calling us at 1.800.322.1189 or

  * emailing us at [privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com](mailto:privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com?)

**your JCPenney credit card account**  
  
---  
  
If you have an account under one of the JCPenney credit programs from Synchrony Bank, a separate privacy policy applies to each program.  The privacy policy describes Synchrony Bank's collection, use, and protection of information about you and your JCPenney credit account. To obtain Synchrony Bank’s privacy policy for your JCPenney credit account, you may:

  * [_click here_](https://www.onlinecreditcenter2.com/JCPenney/occ-privacy.html?&&_ams_security=True) to view Synchrony Bank’s privacy policies in connection with JCPenney Credit programs 
  * write to JCPenney Credit Services/Synchrony Bank at P.O. Box 965007, Orlando, FL 32896-5007, or, 
  * call 1.800.542.0800 (Puerto Rico, U.S. Virgin Islands and Guam residents call 1.800.981.8400)

You can update or correct your name, address, or telephone number for your JCPenney credit account, or check the status of your account by:

  * [_click here_](https://www.onlinecreditcenter2.com/JCPenney/JCPCreditCenter.htm?&&_ams_security=True) to access your JCPenney credit account information on-line 
  * writing to  JCPenney Credit Services/Synchrony Bank at P.O. Box 965007, Orlando, FL 32896-5007
  * call 1.800.542.0800 (Puerto Rico, US Virgin Islands and Guam residents call 1.800.981.8400)

If unauthorized charges (as determined by your card issuer) are made on your credit or debit card as a result of purchases made on jcp.com utilizing our secure servers, JCPenney will reimburse you for up to $50 of any amounts you are required to pay by the card issuer. Also, under the Fair Credit Billing Act, your credit card provider cannot hold you liable for more than $50 of unauthorized charges on a credit card. Your liability for unauthorized use of a debit card may be higher, but many debit card issuers voluntarily apply the $50 limit to their cards as well.

Remember:  In the event of unauthorized use of your credit or debit card, you must promptly notify the card issuer pursuant to its reporting rules and procedures.   
  
**children's privacy**

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 through our websites or mobile applications

**links to other sites and social media widgets**

You may link to other sites from our websites.  Those sites have their own policies regarding privacy.  When you provide personal information at one of those sites, you are subject to the site operator’s privacy policy, not the JCPenney privacy policy. We encourage you to read that policy before submitting any personal information. 

Our websites and our mobile applications include social media features, for example the Facebook Like button, and Facebook, Google Plus, Interest, and Twitter widgets. Social media features or widgets are either hosted by a third - party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with those features are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide them.  
  
**international customer privacy**  
  
JCPenney has contracted with Borderfree, Inc. (“Borderfree”) to facilitate the sale and fulfillment of online purchases that our customers choose to ship internationally (an “international order”).

When you place an international order, you will submit personal information (e.g. your name, email address, billing address, and shipping address) and other order-related information to JCPenney through and to servers located in the United States.  If you also choose to create a jcpenney.com account, any personal information you provide will also be transferred to JCPenney through and to servers located in the United States.  Please note that United States law may not provide a level of data protection equivalent to the laws in your home country.  This privacy policy applies to any personal information you furnish JCPenney in connection with international orders, your jcpenney.com account or otherwise.

JCPenney will then share your international order information, including personal information about you, with Borderfree for the purpose of facilitating ordering and shipping internationally.  Borderfree will process personal information about you in accordance with its [privacy policy. ](http://shop.borderfree.com/privacy-policy) Borderfree has agreed not to sell, transfer, or otherwise use your information other than for processing international orders and shipments.

By placing an international order, you acknowledge and agree that jcp will transfer personal information about you to Borderfree, and acknowledge that your financial transaction and shipment will be processed by Borderfree.  During the checkout process, you will be presented with Borderfree’s terms and conditions and privacy policy.  You must agree to them to receive the product(s) you ordered.

Once your order is approved, JCPenney will ship it to Borderfree.  Simultaneously, Borderfree will purchase the product(s) you ordered from us, which allows them to take title to the product(s), bill your credit card, collect and remit any duties and taxes to the appropriate taxing authorities and arrange for the product(s) to be delivered to you.  In this process, Borderfree makes the sale to you as the merchant of record. 

Customers shipping internationally should email us at [privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com](mailto:privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com?) if they wish to:

  * Inquire about or update their personal information,
  * Make a complaint about the collection or use of their personal information, or
  * Comment on or ask questions regarding this privacy policy,

**changes to this policy**  
  
This policy was last updated on July 24, 2015 and included the following changes:

  * Revision of the “the information we collect” section to provide more detail such as: adding  a reference to “consumer research” in place of the term “focus group;” descriptions of the types of information that we or our service providers may collect or collect automatically, such as information about mobile devices and customers’ use of our mobile applications; and to include an additional use of and opt-out instructions related to location information.
  * Revision of the “using the information we collect” section to include improving products and services and providing location-based and non-location-based notifications as uses for information.  
  * Revision of the “information we share with others” section to add “location awareness” as a service for which we share information with our service providers.
  * Revision of the “cookies and other technologies” section to clarify the types of cookies described in this section; to add the definition of and use for “wireless beacon;” and to clarify fraud detection and prevention among the uses for flash cookies; and to remove the reference to Convertro and its opt-out link. 
  * Updating of the “safeguarding the information we collect” section regarding our service providers’ requirements.
  * Revisions in hyphenation, text, or formatting to clarify, simplify and enhance the readability of this policy.

We may change our privacy policy from time to time.  If we change our privacy policy in the future, we will let you know by posting the updated policy at this website. We encourage you to check our policy periodically. You can tell if it has changed by checking the revision date that appears at the beginning of the policy. If you would like further information, or have any questions about our privacy policy, please:

  * write to us at J. C. Penney Corporation, Inc., P.O. Box 10001, Dallas, TX. 75301-7311, Attention: Corporate Customer Relations
  * call us at 1.800.322.1189
  * email us at [privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com](mailto:privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com?)
